{
    "questions": [
        {
            "Question": "ATM means",
            "optionA": "  All Time Money ",
            "optionB": "  Automatic Teller Machine ",
            "optionC": "  Automated Teller Machine ",
            "optionD": "  Any Time Money ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tATM means Automated Teller Machine. ",
            "keyString": "562971s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "CTBT stands for",
            "optionA": "  Continued Test Ban Treaty ",
            "optionB": "  Continued Test Based Treatments ",
            "optionC": "  Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty ",
            "optionD": "  Commercial Test Based Tariff ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tComprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty is the full form of CTBT. ",
            "keyString": "563000s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "EVM stands for :",
            "optionA": "  Electric Vending Machine ",
            "optionB": "  Electronic Vending Machine ",
            "optionC": "  Electronic Voting Machine ",
            "optionD": "  None of the above ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tEVM stands for Electronic Voting Machine. ",
            "keyString": "563013s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Expand NABARD.",
            "optionA": "  National Bank for Agriculture and Resource Development ",
            "optionB": "  National Bank for Agricultural and Rural Development ",
            "optionC": "  National Bank for Asian Research Development ",
            "optionD": "  National Bank for Agri Related Development ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNABARD stands for National Bank for Agricultural and Rural Development. ",
            "keyString": "563025s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Expand the term IPCC :",
            "optionA": "  International Pollution Control Council ",
            "optionB": "  International Panel of Climate Control ",
            "optionC": "  Interim Panel of Climate Change ",
            "optionD": "  Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tIPCC stands for Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change. ",
            "keyString": "563035s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is the right expansion of TRIMs?",
            "optionA": "  Trade Related Industrial Measures ",
            "optionB": "  Trade Related Innovation Measures ",
            "optionC": "  Trade Related Information Measures ",
            "optionD": "  Trade Related Investment Measures ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTrade Related Investment Measures is the right expansion of TRIMs. ",
            "keyString": "582407s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Expand the term SWIFT.",
            "optionA": "  Society for Worldwide International Financial Telecommunications ",
            "optionB": "  Society for the Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunications ",
            "optionC": "  Society for Worldwide International Financial Transfers ",
            "optionD": "  Society for Worldwide Interbrain Fiscal Transactions ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSociety for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunications is the full form of SWIFT. ",
            "keyString": "612574s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "FIMMDA stands for . . . . . . . . . ",
            "optionA": "  Foreign Investment Market & Derivatives Market Association ",
            "optionB": "  Fixed Income Money Markets & Derivatives Association ",
            "optionC": "  Fixed Income & Money Market Development Association ",
            "optionD": "  Floating Income & Money Markets Derivative Assets ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFIMMDA stands for Fixed Income Money Markets & Derivatives Association. ",
            "keyString": "612604s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Find the odd one out :",
            "optionA": "  IDBI - Financial assistance to large industries ",
            "optionB": "  SIDBI - Financial assistance to small industries ",
            "optionC": "  FCI - Financial assistance to food-grains merchants ",
            "optionD": "  EXIM Bank - Financial assistance to exporters and importers ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFCI, the nodal central agency of Government of India, along with other State Agencies undertakes procurement of wheat and paddy under price support scheme. ",
            "keyString": "612617s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Full form of BCG is :",
            "optionA": "  Bacillus Cholera Germ ",
            "optionB": "  Bacillus Calmette Guerin ",
            "optionC": "  Bacillus Curative Gene ",
            "optionD": "  Bacillus Cholera Guerin ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tBCG, or Bacillus Calmette-Guerin, is a vaccine for tuberculosis (TB) disease. ",
            "keyString": "612629s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "GIS stands for :",
            "optionA": "  Global Institute for Soils ",
            "optionB": "  Geographical International Studies  ",
            "optionC": "  Geographical Information Systems  ",
            "optionD": "  Global Information Statistics ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tGIS stands for Geographical Information Systems. ",
            "keyString": "612640s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The term PC means?",
            "optionA": "  Private Computer ",
            "optionB": "  Personal Computer ",
            "optionC": "  Professional Computer ",
            "optionD": "  Personal Computer ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe term PC means Personal Computer. ",
            "keyString": "659765s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "TRIMs stands for",
            "optionA": "  Trade-Related Income Measures ",
            "optionB": "  Trade-Related Incentives Measures ",
            "optionC": "  Trade-Related Investment Measures ",
            "optionD": "  Trade-Related Innovative Measures ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tTRIMS stands for Trade-Related Investment Measures. ",
            "keyString": "659793s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the expansion of the Indian political coalition, NDA?",
            "optionA": "  National Democratic Alliance ",
            "optionB": "  National Dravidian Alliance ",
            "optionC": "  National Demographic Alliance ",
            "optionD": "  National Defense Alliance ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNational Democratic Alliance is the full form of NDA. ",
            "keyString": "659806s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "What is the full form of ASSOCHAM?",
            "optionA": "  Associated Chambers of Commerce and Industry ",
            "optionB": "  Association of Commerce ",
            "optionC": "  Associated Commerce ",
            "optionD": "  Associated Chambers in India ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tAssociated Chambers of Commerce and Industry is the full form of ASSOCHAM. ",
            "keyString": "659817s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "Which of the following is not correct?",
            "optionA": "  NMA - National Monuments Authority ",
            "optionB": "  SIT - Special Investigation Team ",
            "optionC": "  BSF - British Security Force ",
            "optionD": "  ASI - Archaeological Survey of India ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe full form of BSF is Border Security Force. ",
            "keyString": "659828s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "RMSA means",
            "optionA": "  Rashtriya Madhyamik Shiksha Abhiyan ",
            "optionB": "  Rivers Management and Safety Authority ",
            "optionC": "  Rashtriya Middle School Association ",
            "optionD": "  Recurring Modest Secured Account ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRMSA means Rashtriya Madhyamik Shiksha Abhiyan. ",
            "keyString": "707123s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "SAGAR stands for",
            "optionA": "  South Asian Growth for all in the Region ",
            "optionB": "  Security and Growth for all in the Region ",
            "optionC": "  South Asian Research Journal ",
            "optionD": "  Strategic Agreement for Growth for all in the Region ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSAGAR stands for Security And Growth for All in the Region. ",
            "keyString": "707165s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "SIDBI stands for -",
            "optionA": "  Small Innovations Development Banker's Institute ",
            "optionB": "  Small Industries Development Banker Institute ",
            "optionC": "  Small Industries Development Bank of India ",
            "optionD": "  Small Industrial Design Bank of India ",
            "Answar": " Option C",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tSIDBI stands for Small Industries Development Bank of India. ",
            "keyString": "707177s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The abbreviation LHC stands for which machine?",
            "optionA": "  Long Heavy Collider ",
            "optionB": "  Large Hadron Collider ",
            "optionC": "  Light Heat Collider ",
            "optionD": "  Large High Collider ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe abbreviation LHC stands for Large Hadron Collider. ",
            "keyString": "707190s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "The term GIGO is related to",
            "optionA": "  Accuracy ",
            "optionB": "  Automatic ",
            "optionC": "  Flexibility ",
            "optionD": "  Versatility ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tThe term GIGO is related to accuracy. ",
            "keyString": "707199s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "MODVAT is related to -",
            "optionA": "  Sales tax ",
            "optionB": "  Wealth tax ",
            "optionC": "  Income tax ",
            "optionD": "  Excise Duty ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMODVAT is related to Excise Tax. ",
            "keyString": "737082s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "MRTS stands for :",
            "optionA": "  Mass Rapid Transport System ",
            "optionB": "  Mass Rapid Transit System ",
            "optionC": "  Most Rapid Train Service  ",
            "optionD": "  Mass Rail Transport System ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tMRTS stands for Mass Rapid Transit System. ",
            "keyString": "737111s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "National Agricultural Cooperative Marketing Federation is known as -",
            "optionA": "  NIAM ",
            "optionB": "  NAFED ",
            "optionC": "  MARKFED ",
            "optionD": "  NACMF ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tNational Agricultural Cooperative Marketing Federation is known as NACMF. ",
            "keyString": "737124s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "OTEC stands for - ",
            "optionA": "  Ocean Thermal Energy Conservation ",
            "optionB": "  Oil and Thermal Energy Conservation ",
            "optionC": "  Oil and Thermal Energy Convention ",
            "optionD": "  Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tOTEC stands for Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion. ",
            "keyString": "737135s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "RAF is the abbreviated form of which of the following?",
            "optionA": "  Ready Action Force ",
            "optionB": "  Rapid Action Force ",
            "optionC": "  Reverse Action Force ",
            "optionD": "  Repeat Action Force ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tRAF is the abbreviated form of Rapid Action Force. ",
            "keyString": "737145s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "In India FERA has been replaced by?",
            "optionA": "  FEMA ",
            "optionB": "  FETA ",
            "optionC": "  FENA ",
            "optionD": "  FELA ",
            "Answar": " Option A",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tFERA was repealed in 1998 by the government of Atal Bihari Vajpayee and replaced by the Foreign Exchange Management Act (FEMA), which liberalised foreign exchange controls and restrictions on foreign investment. ",
            "keyString": "803202s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "ISRO is the abbreviation for -",
            "optionA": "  Indian Scientific Research Organisation ",
            "optionB": "  Indian Space Research Organisation ",
            "optionC": "  International Space Research Organisation ",
            "optionD": "  International Scientific Research Organisation ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tISRO is the abbreviation for Indian Space Research Organisation. ",
            "keyString": "803236s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "JDBC stands for :",
            "optionA": "  Java Developer Connectivity ",
            "optionB": "  Java Database Connectivity ",
            "optionC": "  Java Developing Connectivity ",
            "optionD": "  Java Database Conductivity ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tJDBC stands for Java Database Connectivity. ",
            "keyString": "803252s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "JIMEX 2018 related to",
            "optionA": "  Japan-India Joint Military Exhibition ",
            "optionB": "  Japan-India Maritime Exercise ",
            "optionC": "  Japan-India Joint Motor Vehicle Exhibition ",
            "optionD": "  Japan-India Joint Missile Programme ",
            "Answar": " Option B",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tJIMEX 2018 relates to Japan-India Maritime Exercise. ",
            "keyString": "803265s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        },
        {
            "Question": "LAN stands for",
            "optionA": "  Local Area Nodes ",
            "optionB": "  Large Area Network ",
            "optionC": "  Large Area Nodes ",
            "optionD": "  Local Area Network ",
            "Answar": " Option D",
            "solution": " Solution:\t\tLAN stands for Local Area Network. ",
            "keyString": "803278s2m23h16d15m7y2021",
            "isBookMark": 0,
            "isShown": 0,
            "isCon": 0
        }
    ]
}